<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>James' Digital Garden</title><link>https://idiosapps.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on James' Digital Garden</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>James Clark Â©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://idiosapps.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Indian Jones &amp; the font of accessibility</title><link>https://idiosapps.github.io/garden/font-of-accessibility/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idiosapps.github.io/garden/font-of-accessibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>// DEMONSTRATE font A vs B legibility (extreme case: windings? VS hyperlegible)
// bit about hyperlegible&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// IMAGE of indian jones faces melting &amp;ldquo;when some people see comic sans used unironically&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// QUOTE? Simon Peython Jones - major contributor to the Haskell programming language, outreach&lt;/p>
&lt;p>comic sans - which variants, and where you can use them. short section for each, with references
0. this website&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>desktop browser&lt;/li>
&lt;li>samsung phone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>kindle (easier reading/smaller font/different vibe)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IDE code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>terminal&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>// Reference back to clickbait summary&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// CTA - try out some new fonts in new places&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>James Clark</title><link>https://idiosapps.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idiosapps.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;del>I have a reddish-brown fur, a long, shaggy tail, and a waddling gait due to my shorter front legs; I&amp;rsquo;m roughly the size of a domestic cat, though with a longer body.&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="things-i-like">Things I like&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ðŸŽ® Some of my favourite games were/are Overwatch, Guild Wars, anything by Supergiant Games, It Takes Two, Destiny 2, a few Mario games&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great games! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to playing a bunch of stuff on Xbox Games Pass for PC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ“– &amp;ldquo;Graphic novels&amp;rdquo; (comics) are my go-to reading material. I recommend Saga, The Best we Could Do, and Asterios Polyp. Text and images can be very expressive and also let you digest at your own page. There&amp;rsquo;s major educational potential too: the &amp;ldquo;Peterloo&amp;rdquo; historical graphic novel is one to read if you like Manchester!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>â™¨ï¸ Cooking is tasty and interesting, and I like quality equipment (Vitamix, non-non-stick oven trays, etc.) - but it can be a chore at the end of a long day. Do let me know if you have any meal prep tips!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ“Š Noting down information (such as comparisons on blenders, coffee machines, oven trays&amp;hellip; most stuff I need to buy that I&amp;rsquo;ll use a lot) to make sure I make a good decision&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸš wagamama&amp;rsquo;s menu &amp;amp; website - it&amp;rsquo;s all in lower case; do you need captial letters when you use space well?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="things-i-dont-like">Things I don&amp;rsquo;t like&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ðŸ’¥ Sudden, loud noises - dogs/fireworks/balloons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>â˜€ï¸ Being woken up too early by the sun, or birdsong&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸŸï¸ Crowded, busy places - home &amp;amp; lonely nature is preferable&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="interesting-facts">Interesting facts&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â›©ï¸ After graduating I taught in Shanghai, China for one year; I then spent all my money travelling China, South Korea, and Japan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ’¬ When learning Mandarin as an adult, I got more interested in second language acquisition / &lt;em>how&lt;/em> to learn languages. This led to me making my first original piece of code (a &amp;ldquo;graded reader&amp;rdquo; book builder), and now I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>âœï¸ This website uses the font called &amp;ldquo;Comic Neue&amp;rdquo; - and so does my phone. My IDE has &amp;ldquo;Comic Mono&amp;rdquo;, a monospaced variant. It might get some hate being based on &amp;ldquo;Comic Sans&amp;rdquo; - but it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be easier to read (especially for people with dyslexia), and I like it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸŽ¹ I recently taught myself how to solve a Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cube, and now I&amp;rsquo;m playing some (basic) piano again&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="how-i-work--how-to-communicate-with-me">How I work / how to communicate with me&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ðŸ“ I like to have information written down - it can be revisited, shared, and quoted/referenced. I&amp;rsquo;m probably writing my own notes in meetings when I feel there&amp;rsquo;s something important to capture!
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/">Notion&lt;/a> is my main tool to capture information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I prefer bullet-points over paragraphs, to keep ideas focused&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ—º Even better than having text written down, I like to see visuals. Pictures speak a thousand words. Multiple pictures give an intuitive demonstrate of change over time. As I said: I like comics. I appreciate the irony that there are not many pictures here.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.tldraw.com/">tldraw&lt;/a> helps me sketch out ideas. It has a collaborative mode. Miro and Lucid are good too.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://mermaid-js.github.io/">mermaid&lt;/a> is a tool I want to use more - &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/architecture/sequence-diagrams-enrich-your-understanding-of-distributed-architectures/">Diagrams as Code&lt;/a> sound amazing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ¤« Quiet environments with minimal distractions are ideal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ‘¥ Pair programming/mobbing is my preferred way of working. Social knowledge share and discussion in the comfort of your own home is a great combination&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="other-topicsquestions-to-expand-on">Other topics/questions to expand on&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What motivates me?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What qualities do I value in people?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How would I like to give &amp;amp; receive feedback?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What makes me laugh?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>