<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>team on James' Digital Garden</title><link>https://james-s-w-clark.github.io/garden_tags/team/</link><description>Recent content in team on James' Digital Garden</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>James Clark ©</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://james-s-w-clark.github.io/garden_tags/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Games for work socials</title><status>growing</status><link>https://james-s-w-clark.github.io/garden/games-for-socials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://james-s-w-clark.github.io/garden/games-for-socials/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever since COVID became a thing in our daily lives, remote work has become more prevalent. Whilst there&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount to gain from remote working, we do lose those colloquial chats by the water cooler or board/card games in lunch breaks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my experience, it&amp;rsquo;s common for companies to offer a 1-2 hour social meeting on Fridays - maybe just to chat, or with a game at the forefront.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years now since COVID started, and we&amp;rsquo;ve all tried lots of games. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of games you should try, and what I think about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="free">Free&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Game&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Rating / 5 stars&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://tagpro.koalabeast.com/">TagPro&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Gameplay will be 90% of the focus of your social. Great fun - be sure to make an account and change your name so you can get more teamwork going on!&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>| &lt;a href="https://virtualvacation.us">VirtualVacation&lt;/a> | 4 | Like GeoGuessr, but with a video - and everyone can have their own guess!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>| &lt;a href="https://www.geoguessr.com">GeoGuessr&lt;/a> | 4 | Move around Google Maps Streetview and work as a team to guess where you are!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>| &lt;a href="https://quackstanley.net/">QuackStanley&lt;/a> | 5 | Much like Snakeoil, a “buyer” is offered goods from each other player in turn (based on a choice of 2 of 4 topics). Weird and creative, and super fast to pick up |
| &lt;a href="https://surelook.github.io/countdown/">Countdown&lt;/a> | 4.5 | The classic British game CountDown, with both word/number/pre-generated anagram challenges, a big block, and even the music! Everyone plays at the same time, and competes to find the highest score. | | | |
| &lt;a href="https://www.drawasaurus.org/">Drawasaurus&lt;/a> | 4 | You&amp;rsquo;re either drawing or typing in a thoughtful frenzy to guess what one player&amp;rsquo;s drawing is. I like how this game keeps everyone involved, and is leninet on spelling mistakes |
| &lt;a href="https://codenames.game/">Codenames&lt;/a> | 4 | The classic word-game Codenames - be sure to set a timer so people don&amp;rsquo;t take 7 minutes to find the perfect clues (which may not even work!) |
| &lt;a href="https://globle-game.com/">Globle&lt;/a> | 4 | Guess where a mystery country is! |
| &lt;a href="https://www.teambridge.app/">TeamBridge.app&lt;/a> | 3.5 | There&amp;rsquo;s 6 free games, but they&amp;rsquo;re pretty quiet. For example, Cosel (&amp;ldquo;broken telephone&amp;rdquo;) has e.g. 10 people drawing and describing plenty of images, which takes a lot of focus; the fun comes when the whole group sees how words evolved. But it&amp;rsquo;s cute and there&amp;rsquo;s variety, so give it a try one week! |
| &lt;a href="https://chameleon-roan.vercel.app/">Chameleon&lt;/a> | 3 | For a category (animals, fruits, etc.) all but one player see the same word. They give clues to show they know what the word is - but not enough obvious information so that the &amp;ldquo;chameleon&amp;rdquo; can guess the word and blend in with the group! | | | |
| &lt;a href="https://gjeuken.github.io/telewave/">Wavelength&lt;/a> | 2.5 | An ingenius digital board for the game &amp;ldquo;Wavelength&amp;rdquo; - be sure to read the instructions. I find it so difficult to think of a word on the spot such that this game isn&amp;rsquo;t really fun to me - but discussing and guessing other people&amp;rsquo;s words is OK |
| &lt;a href="https://www.hanab.cards/">Hanab&lt;/a> | ? | A cooperative game where a team of pyrotechnics give each other information to build 5 fireworks |
| &lt;a href="https://categories-with-friends.herokuapp.com/">Categories with Friends/Scattergories&lt;/a> | ? | Each player writes a word with each category, getting double points if it matches the round&amp;rsquo;s special letter. Think someone has made something up? A quick vote will settle it! | | | |&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="paid">Paid&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Game&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Rating / 5 stars&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.jackboxgames.com/">Jackbox Games&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>There’s a number of releases, each with their own mix of &lt;a href="https://www.jackboxgames.com/games/">hit-or-miss games&lt;/a>. Fibbage, Quiplash, and Drawful Animate are my favourites (2 of these are in the &lt;a href="https://www.jackboxgames.com/party-pack-two/">second party pack&lt;/a>)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Among Us &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/945360/Among_Us/">PC (paid)&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.innersloth.spacemafia&amp;amp;hl=en_GB&amp;amp;gl=US">Play Store&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/among-us/id1351168404">App Store&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>?&lt;/td>
&lt;td>People were genuinely playing this every day at work during the height of its popularity. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> it, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic social game&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://colonist.io/">Catan&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>?&lt;/td>
&lt;td>There&amp;rsquo;s a nice UI and maybe more expansions than with BoardGameArena (?), so if you keep playing Catan this might be a good choice.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://boardgamearena.com/gamelist">BoardGameArena&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>?&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Play games like Catan, Azul, Wingspan, Ticket to Ride, Sushi Go - but one member needs a premium subscription (£27/year, or £5/month)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>